

Profile

Web developer with more than a decade of experience in creating and maintaining systems. He has been working with Ruby on Rails for seven years. Focused on solving problems, producing tested, refactored, clean and effective source code. Dedicated to the development process, it does not dispense with the use of agile methodologies. Able to self-manage effectively during projects, as well as collaborate as part of a team. Willing to improve, grow and always deliver values to organizations.

Now he is dedicated to the study of the development of large-scale applications, with microservices, event driven, hexagonal architecture, and the study of the Go language.

Employment History

Senior Software Engineer, Pontomais, Curitiba - PR

JANUARY 2021 — PRESENT

HR system experience building highly concurrent and low latency backend systems and frontend interfaces.

Development and maintaining API REST and integrations (public API).

Analysis and development of new features, as well as revamp existing features.

Practice areas: RH Tech

Full Stack Developer, ASSEINFO, Tijucas - SC

JULY 2007 — DECEMBER 2020

13+ years of ERP systems experience building backend applications and frontend interfaces.

Building back-end services and APIs to support new and existing product initiatives

Analysis and development of new features, as well as revamp existing features.

Building asynchronous services.

Mentoring new team members.

Practice areas: ERP (inventory, finance, billing, production).

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, Universidade do Vale do Itajaí (UNIVALI), Itajaí - SC

MARCH 2006 — JULY 2012

Courses

Golang, School of Net

FEBRUARY 2021 — FEBRUARY 2020

Details

São João Batista - SC, Brasil +55 48 991450518 linielsonrosa@gmail.com

Links

github.com/linielson linkedin.com/in/linielson

Skills

Programming languages: Ruby, JavaScript, Golang, SQL, CSS, HTML, Delphi

Frameworks: Ruby on Rails (RoR), Bootstrap, AngularJS

Libraries: React, jQuery, Redux, FactoryBot, VCR, SimpleCov, Rubocop

Tools: Git, GitHub, CircleCl, Codeclimate, Webpack, Sidekiq, Apiary, RSpec, Jest, Cypress, Protractor, Karma, Jasmine

Best practices: Clean Code, Refactory, DRY, Code Review

Paradigms: OOP, DDD, MVC, TDD,

Agile methodologies: Lean, Kanban, XP, Scrum

DB: PostgreSQL, Redis

Infrastructure: Docker, Heroku

Practice areas: ERP (inventory, finance, billing, production), HR Tech

Others: API REST, Lean inception

Languages

Inglês